

Summary

5 years of experience mainly with backend related technologies.
Also interested in DevOps and data science solutions as well.
Eager to continuously learn while working on challenging projects within a team.

Contact

- Budapest, Hungary
- zoltan.umlauf@gmail.com
- in /in/zoltan-umlauf
- /uzoltan

Languages

English: professional working proficiency

Hungarian: native proficiency

Interests

- Table tennis
- Reading
- Board games
- Hiking
- Logic puzzles
- Software craftsmanship

Zoltán Umlauf

Work Experience

Senior Software Engineer

@ Turbine AI

09/2021 - Present 🗘

- Designed and developed new features in Turbine's human cell simulation platform, making the jobs of biologists more efficient.
- Constructed machine learning problems to train deep learning models. Evaluated these models on various success criteria.
- Learned many exciting technologies (e.g. version-controlled database, CICD pipeline tools) and an interesting problem domain about how to model a human cell.
- Significantly improved the quality of existing production code.
- Performed a wide range of data engineering tasks.

Python, Poetry, Pandas, Azure Cloud, AzureML, Databricks, Airflow, Terraform, Dolt, MongoDB

Senior Software Developer

@ Grape Solutions

03/2019 - 08/2021

- Developed <u>Mobiliti</u>, the largest provider of electric vehicle charging and other e-mobility services in Hungary.
- Discussed software architecture decisions with the team.
- Proposed ways to improve the development workflow.
- Documented important domain knowledge, promoted knowledge sharing and gathering practices.
- Planned and executed the integration with 4 Charge Point Operators.
- Learned the basics of DevOps with Docker and Kubernetes.

Java 11, Kotlin, Spring Boot 2, Reactive Streams, Liquibase, JUnit5, Mockito, Wiremock, Gradle, Docker, Google Cloud Platform (PubSub, Firestore), MySQL, MongoDB, Python

Education



MSc in Electrical Engineering

@ Budapest University of Technology and Economics

02/2016 - 01/2018 (

• Thesis: Data processing methods and solutions in IoT based Cyber-Physical Systems

See my full resume at <u>uzoltan.github.io</u>.